<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>valleybay</title>
 <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2017-10-11T00:45:35+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://valleybay.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Christian Bay</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>One more thing</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/one-more-thing/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T00:22:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/one-more-thing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh. One more thing. A week ago I disabled notifications for Messenger and Snapchat.
I was hoping that this would help me relax and disconnect. It sort of has. But it’s
still not good enough. I actually considered deleting Snapchat and Messenger, but
that seems over the top. They’re fun &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt;. Any way, disabling notifications
is not enough, because now I have to go into the applications to see if I have any
new messages. This is annoying (and disappointing) when I don’t have any new messages
(sad face). I guess I just need to be more disciplined. Move them to a separate screen,
keep badge count on (so I don’t have to open the app), and then only check every 3-4 hours.
We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How am I doing</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/how-am-i-doing/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T00:15:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/how-am-i-doing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok. So I am getting a bit tired. I actually was making some good progress, until Dropbox halted me
with some sort of service disruption. I’ve been doing some testing on an EC2 instance on AWS, where
I’ll be hosting the dropbox service integration server.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve got basic functionality working, but there’s a lot of code to be written. No chance that it’ll
be done today. Apparently Dropbox will be hitting the notification endpoint every single time a file
is changed / added, and that can happen multiple times when I’m editing the file. That means that it
won’t be enough to just generate some file and commit that to GitHub. I’ll have to set some upper
limit on how often this actually can happen… Probably won’t be too big of a deal, but it still adds
some complexity. Oh well. I’ll soldier on. (I’m soon going to bed). (I think).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On a more positive note</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/on-a-more-positive-note/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T20:55:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/on-a-more-positive-note</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love this writing thing. Spamming out shit in my own tempo. I can get used to this.
I’m cooking some rice now. Ricealicious. Sooo delicious. Listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/spotify/playlist/37i9dQZF1DX6kz6Kli3wib&quot;&gt;this playlist&lt;/a&gt;.
Chill out dinner is a winner.&lt;br /&gt;
So, I’ve come up with a brilliant ploy to post to this blog. See, it is hosted on GitHub, and I have to actually commit the posts to a repository in order for them to show up here.
I want to post from an app on my phone, tablet or mac (Writer). I’ll write files that will be stored in my Dropbox. I’ve created an application for Dropbox that will hit a server,
I’ll download that file, format it properly, then commit it to GitHub. Voila motherfucker.&lt;br /&gt;
If I’m really awesome, I’ll get all of that to work tonight. Probably not. Maybe tomorrow. Anyway, I’ll keep you posted. xoxo.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Exploiters, fakers, hacks</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/exploiters-fakers-hacks/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T20:30:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/exploiters-fakers-hacks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got some time on your hands? Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://meaningness.com/geeks-mops-sociopaths&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.
It’s important.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s happening, and it’s been happening for a long time. The innovation scene is picking up steam,
it’s been picking up steam for so long that it’s nearly over. It’s getting &lt;em&gt;popular&lt;/em&gt;. Associating
yourself with innovation is becoming &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt;. It’s time to get off that train, because a shitstorm
is forming.&lt;br /&gt;
Why are you doing what you’re doing? Is it because you love it? Because you believe you can improve
it? Or are you just in it for your own good. The cash and glory? If it is the latter; go fuck yourself.
All the ICOs these days.. I’m tripping. Fucking hacks. Tired of them. Do something real for once, will ya?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Next Big Thing</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/the-next-big-thing/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T17:46:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/the-next-big-thing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Zero To One, Peter Thiel claims that the next Facebook won’t be a social network.
I think the next big thing won’t even be a company. We’re constantly thinking about
companies, about profit. Well guess what, I’m tired of profit. We don’t need more money.
Individuals do not need a lot of money. We don’t need most of the stuff we consume.
It’s a system that feeds itself. We use advertising to make people desire things, so
that we can do a wealth transfer between individuals. People do not actually want those
things, you are tricking them into wanting it. Ok, so fuck companies. It’s all rotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s next? Something that isn’t a company. Is it a non-profit? Perhaps, but not the
kind of non-profit we see today. I think something in between. Non-profits that sell
things and generate revenue, but that don’t make any profit. Now that’s interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to work out. Later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Van life for real</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life-for-real/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T12:54:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life-for-real</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have a look at this guys &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruby-on-wheels.github.io/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Now I really want to do van life.
He even has his own solar panles on the roof, and custom antennas for better 4G coverage. I’m doing van life
at some point! I need to get a remote job. I sort of have one, but I need to make the one I have more remote,
and then I need to get a programming gig. I’ll contact some companies today. Am I really doing van life? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fixing a lot of stuff on this page today. Added a link to an about page in the footer. Now I just need
to make some sort of system for posting remotely. It’s either the Writer iCloud/Dropbox thing, or just post
from e-mail. Posting from e-mail sounds alluring. Ok. I need breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Van Life</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T11:50:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just woke up. I read about someone living in a van, driving around the country, 
remote coding as a living. I like that idea. Sometimes I think that it would be
cool to live as a nomad coder. It’s just that I like comfort too much. Maybe 
somtime.&lt;br /&gt;
Today I want to keep working on my setup, and I want to do something about this
microblog. I don’t know if I am happy using jekyll to host it, although it 
certainly is the simplest.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Emacs</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/emacs/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-09T04:28:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/emacs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve given Emacs another try this week. This time I did it properly.&lt;br /&gt;
I set up everything from scratch. Backed up my Spacemacs config, and let it all go.
Every time I start using Emacs I have a dream that this piece of software will do everything for me. It won’t.&lt;br /&gt;
So I’m back on my vim+tmux setup. I’ll probably keep using org-mode in Spacemacs, like I used to. I’ll write some more about this when I’m not supertired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s super annoying, because I’m struggling to get this site to order my posts based on the date+time they were created. No such luck yet. Going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>System for posting</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/system-for-posting/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-09T03:38:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/system-for-posting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before I go to bed. I need to create some sort of system that will allow me to post from my phone etc.
I think I can do that with something like crontab polling my Dropbox/iCloud. Probably harder with iCloud,
but I really don’t want to go back to syncing my Writer documents on Dropbox. Actually, that isn’t happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what’s going to be painful? Having to manually control the damn line-breaks. Whatever. I’ll get used to it (or find a workaround).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Universe</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/the-universe/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-09T01:35:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/the-universe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The universe, life, is profoundly sad&lt;br /&gt;
Here now, only to be erased,&lt;br /&gt;
By the razorblade of time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are even dreams,&lt;br /&gt;
But nights cruel mistress,&lt;br /&gt;
Painting hope, on our days&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we even move,&lt;br /&gt;
But in lock-step with it all&lt;br /&gt;
Again – and again,&lt;br /&gt;
It comes to break my heart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this poem about one year ago. I think it’s the best I’ve ever written.&lt;br /&gt;
Listening to Written On The Sky by Max Richter it sprung into existense.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
