<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>valleybay</title>
 <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2017-10-13T20:28:56+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://valleybay.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Christian Bay</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Ideas for future posts</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/13/things-i-want-to-say/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-13T20:15:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/13/things-i-want-to-say</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post will only serve as a list of things that I want to post about at some
point in the future. I will nudge it to the top every time I update it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designer babies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Humans are machines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The right to suicide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life’s role in entropy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fashioning tools to overcome anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The anxiety of God: God’s imminent fear of not being God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Half way</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/half-way/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T14:35:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/half-way</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier I haven’t been able to produce much. Or… I’ve produced a lot,
but I haven’t really finished anything. I’ve seen this as a flaw. It annoys
me that my projects never get anywhere. I’d try to write, create music, design
something, come up with novel products. So many ideas that never amount to
anything fully tangible. But! I just had an idea. The piano does that to you.&lt;br /&gt;
What if I am looking at it entirely wrong? What if my role isn’t to finish things,
but just come up with lots of random stuff? It doesn’t need to be polished. I just
need to think the thought, to sketch it out, show it to other people, and they can
take it from there. Thing is, this didn’t work for me before, because I had to 
earn money, and giving away your ideas for free won’t earn you anything. My new model
for life is that I don’t think about money; I just work, and (enough) money will appear.&lt;br /&gt;
So in practical terms, what does this mean? It means that I will have to publish all the
stuff I produce. If I create a new melody, publish that son of a gun. A new idea? 
Put it on the microblog. You see, I’ve been to vain. I’ve been caring too much about
what other people think of me, through their opinions of what I make. That’s vanity.
I will improve, through publishing everything I create, near moment of
inception.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Inspo has a price</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/inspo-has-a-price/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T14:22:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/inspo-has-a-price</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspiration can be a dangerous thing. After getting inspired by someone,
I too often compare myself to them. When considering what I am doing,
stepping through scenarios, I try to see that same thing with their eyes.
Compare my habits, to their habits. Just now I was playing the piano,
and I was thinking: “but Jony Ive and Steve both work during the day time,
if they do most their work around other people, I should be able to do
that too”. These are the perils of inspiration. Just because we get inspired,
we need to control just how much of their habits and thoughts we should
integrate into our own lives. Two lives are remarkably different,
and so they must be led.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day time</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/day-time/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T14:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/day-time</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Day time is hard for me. I have no clue what to do. There are a lot of things
that I could be doing, but none of them are tempting. I feel weird during daytime.
I actually had a period where I’d go to bed 08.00 and sleep till 16.00. Needless
to say, that was a programming period, where I didn’t do anything else besides writing
software.&lt;br /&gt;
I feel like shit during the day. It’s hard to explain. My body isn’t cooperating, it’s
too bright, and I’m too aware of the fact that people are doing shit everywhere.
Outside, kids are screaming, I hear the sounds of roadworkers and all sorts of noisy
machinery. Also, I’m sort of uninspired. Thing is, the mornings are fine. Early 
mornings are OK. At least for working out, answering e-mails. Aha! It’s the computer.
I don’t like computers during daytime. That’s weird.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Steve</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/steve/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T13:12:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/steve</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before going to bed last night, and this morning, I’ve been watching videos
about Steve Jobs. I’ve been interested in Apple’s employees and their products
since I was 16 years old, but I haven’t been thinking about it that much the
last years. As they became behemoths of popularity, I peered into other parts
of the world. It’s good that I came back, though, because I had forgotten how
much Apple used to inspire me.&lt;br /&gt;
When Jonathan Ive speaks of Steve, it’s with an enamouration for his childlike
joy and sense of civic responsibility. Steve created the products because he 
felt like they needed to be perfect. Not because he wanted the admiration or
the cheque. I need that sort of inspiration. I need to see that other people
feel this way. It’s what keeps me going. The feeling that
someone deeply cares about something, about a product.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>One more thing</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/one-more-thing/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T00:22:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/one-more-thing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh. One more thing. A week ago I disabled notifications for Messenger and Snapchat.
I was hoping that this would help me relax and disconnect. It sort of has. But it’s
still not good enough. I actually considered deleting Snapchat and Messenger, but
that seems over the top. They’re fun &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt;. Any way, disabling notifications
is not enough, because now I have to go into the applications to see if I have any
new messages. This is annoying (and disappointing) when I don’t have any new messages
(sad face). I guess I just need to be more disciplined. Move them to a separate screen,
keep badge count on (so I don’t have to open the app), and then only check every 3-4 hours.
We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How am I doing</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/how-am-i-doing/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T00:15:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/11/how-am-i-doing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok. So I am getting a bit tired. I actually was making some good progress, until Dropbox halted me
with some sort of service disruption. I’ve been doing some testing on an EC2 instance on AWS, where
I’ll be hosting the dropbox service integration server.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve got basic functionality working, but there’s a lot of code to be written. No chance that it’ll
be done today. Apparently Dropbox will be hitting the notification endpoint every single time a file
is changed / added, and that can happen multiple times when I’m editing the file. That means that it
won’t be enough to just generate some file and commit that to GitHub. I’ll have to set some upper
limit on how often this actually can happen… Probably won’t be too big of a deal, but it still adds
some complexity. Oh well. I’ll soldier on. (I’m soon going to bed). (I think).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Next Big Thing</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/the-next-big-thing/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T17:46:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/the-next-big-thing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Zero To One, Peter Thiel claims that the next Facebook won’t be a social network.
I think the next big thing won’t even be a company. We’re constantly thinking about
companies, about profit. Well guess what, I’m tired of profit. We don’t need more money.
Individuals do not need a lot of money. We don’t need most of the stuff we consume.
It’s a system that feeds itself. We use advertising to make people desire things, so
that we can do a wealth transfer between individuals. People do not actually want those
things, you are tricking them into wanting it. Ok, so fuck companies. It’s all rotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s next? Something that isn’t a company. Is it a non-profit? Perhaps, but not the
kind of non-profit we see today. I think something in between. Non-profits that sell
things and generate revenue, but that don’t make any profit. Now that’s interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to work out. Later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Van life for real</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life-for-real/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T12:54:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life-for-real</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have a look at this guys &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruby-on-wheels.github.io/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Now I really want to do van life.
He even has his own solar panles on the roof, and custom antennas for better 4G coverage. I’m doing van life
at some point! I need to get a remote job. I sort of have one, but I need to make the one I have more remote,
and then I need to get a programming gig. I’ll contact some companies today. Am I really doing van life? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fixing a lot of stuff on this page today. Added a link to an about page in the footer. Now I just need
to make some sort of system for posting remotely. It’s either the Writer iCloud/Dropbox thing, or just post
from e-mail. Posting from e-mail sounds alluring. Ok. I need breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Van Life</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-10T11:50:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/10/van-life</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just woke up. I read about someone living in a van, driving around the country, 
remote coding as a living. I like that idea. Sometimes I think that it would be
cool to live as a nomad coder. It’s just that I like comfort too much. Maybe 
somtime.&lt;br /&gt;
Today I want to keep working on my setup, and I want to do something about this
microblog. I don’t know if I am happy using jekyll to host it, although it 
certainly is the simplest.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Emacs</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/emacs/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-09T04:28:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/emacs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve given Emacs another try this week. This time I did it properly.&lt;br /&gt;
I set up everything from scratch. Backed up my Spacemacs config, and let it all go.
Every time I start using Emacs I have a dream that this piece of software will do everything for me. It won’t.&lt;br /&gt;
So I’m back on my vim+tmux setup. I’ll probably keep using org-mode in Spacemacs, like I used to. I’ll write some more about this when I’m not supertired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s super annoying, because I’m struggling to get this site to order my posts based on the date+time they were created. No such luck yet. Going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>System for posting</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/system-for-posting/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-09T03:38:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2017/10/09/system-for-posting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before I go to bed. I need to create some sort of system that will allow me to post from my phone etc.
I think I can do that with something like crontab polling my Dropbox/iCloud. Probably harder with iCloud,
but I really don’t want to go back to syncing my Writer documents on Dropbox. Actually, that isn’t happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what’s going to be painful? Having to manually control the damn line-breaks. Whatever. I’ll get used to it (or find a workaround).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
