<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Valleybay</title>
 <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-11-05T11:32:07+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://valleybay.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Christian Bay</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The death of the (old) Internet</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2016/11/05/death-of-the-internet/"/>
   <updated>2016-11-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2016/11/05/death-of-the-internet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.happyassassin.net/2016/11/04/i-dont-like-computers/&quot;&gt;a blogpost&lt;/a&gt; where the author proclaims he does not like computers anymore. A decade ago computers were ours. We used to geek out playing games and hang around IRC. I still seldomly do both, but it’s not the same anymore. The cool people have ruined the Internet. Partly by just being themselves, but mostly because when they arrived a lot of big businesses startet pushing their shit onto the network, and that’s my point. Today everyone is selling something on the internet. Mostly if you aren’t selling any products, you’re still selling some cool version of yourself, and this gets tiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;theres-just-too-much&quot;&gt;There’s just too much&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I open up HackerNews there’s some shiny new software, hardware product, or novel idea. Every time. I don’t even get time to digest it, because if I come back later, there’s a new thing for me to look at. There is so much money slushing around, that people will do nearly anything to get some of it. We make tons of stuff, and claim we make it “for fun”, but the truth is we make it so that we can show it off, get recognition or hopefully, even better, get hired by some company that appreciate our skills. But what happens when EVERYONE starts doing this? There is a content explosion. There’s just too much stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-optimization-trap&quot;&gt;The optimization trap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not fully true what I said about people not making stuff for fun. Some people do. But they also do it because they are bored, and don’t have anything to do anymore. In the past more people had to work manual jobs, performing laborious tasks, but these jobs are being automated. But this also means that things are becoming more and more efficient, which frees up our time to do other things. We spend less and less of our time doing time consuming tasks, and this leaves us with a lot of spare time. So what do we do? We want to get entertained: television, smartphones and computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that a lot of people are spending most of their time on the Internet, what happens? The money, and specifically the ad money appears. So there’s so much money around that everyone wants to make more money. So we start producing tons of content on YouTube, Netflix, HBO, to name a few. And what happens then? Well, people see these companies making a lot of money too, so they want to make new platforms. But there’s a trap. In the end there’s more content being made, than eyes to watch it, because the human machine is not capable of too much stimulus. It will collapse. Over-entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason the author doesn’t like the Internet anymore is because before it was a separate dimension. It was somewhere to hide, somewhere for us to be ourselves and have fun. Now the Internet has synced with society, and boy have they cloud. It’s just a shitstorm. If we want to make our computers fun again, we need to escape to our own dimension &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;. We can do it. It’s what we’ve always done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Information is everywhere</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2016/10/30/information-is-everywhere/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2016/10/30/information-is-everywhere</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does a view, a picture on the wall, a TV show or a newspaper all have in common? They’re all compositions of information. When staring out the window, or looking at the photos on your wall, you’re consuming data about the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We surround ourselves with things to feel better. We hang photos of our friends on the wall, so that we’ll feel happy looking back on our past. We’re constantly using information from the past to feel better in the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been at my best in low information rooms. White walls and only the things I require. I don’t want anything to disturb my process. It’s the same feeling I get in large open spaces, they somehow fail to segment the information in an interesting way. I just feel overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Just the concept</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2016/10/29/just-the-concept/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2016/10/29/just-the-concept</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In writing we are encouraged to be somewhat verbose. Texts are to be of a certain length in order to fit the mould. 
But I’d prefer if you didn’t delay the point for too long. It’s like with milk, I don’t want the cow, I just want the milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the idea behind concept-only writing. Just give me the concept, short and succinct, and let me figure out what it means to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What and Why</title>
   <link href="http://valleybay.github.io/2016/10/28/what-and-why/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://valleybay.github.io/2016/10/28/what-and-why</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking of writing for some time, it’s just that I never get started. When I do get started, I never finish what I write, and that’s exactly what I intend on doing here: never get started and never finish what I start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently started sharing my thoughts on Twitter. Thing is, tweets are too short and tweets are too permanent. I also briefly experimented with Medium, but quickly found it too noisy, so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is simply a place for me to beam ideas and thoughts from my phone to your brain. Do not expect well written stuff here, and don’t be surprised if the posts are littered with typos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for why, I’m just sharing my thoughts because I think some of them are interesting. If you’d like to have a chat about anything you read here, message me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chrisvalleybay&quot;&gt;@chrisvalleybay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final disclaimer I should say that I plan on adding or removing from any of these posts without any indication of doing so. All prior versions are however checked into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/valleybay/valleybay.github.io&quot;&gt;git repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
